Eniola Babatunde

Geographical Information Science Graduate

CONTACT

07405480589 enniebabs@gmail.com

203, Forest Road. Loughborough

https://arcg.is/aSOWG

ITSKILLS

- ArcGIS 10.4
- · JavaScript/jQuery
- Python (inc. numpy)
- SQL
- ArcPv
- QGIS
- ENVI
- R (inc. ggplot2, ggmap)
- ArcGIS Online (inc story maps)
- Leaflet

LEADERSHIP SKILLS

- Tutoring classmates and other students through coursework at undergraduate level
- Class representative and team lead for field survey projects
- Proper remittance of funds as financial secretary of student society

PROFILE

Tenacious geographical information enthusiast with over one-year commercial experience, adaptable to changing priorities, with experience in spatial analysis, remote sensing and mapping. Creative ability to problem solving and working independently. Thrives in multidisciplinary team settings, keen to learn new work practices, procedures and technical skills in-line with client requirements.

EDUCATION

MSc. Geographical Information Science University of Edinburgh | 2017 – 2018

World class GIS programme, developing strong practical skills with fundamental theoretical knowledge to support the application of GIS skills in any software environment.

Providing vast amount of knowledge in advanced spatial analysis, geovisualisation, project planning, and mapping with an excellent grounding in GI technology.

Modules included:

- · Spatial Modelling and Analysis
- · Technological Infrastructures for GIS
- · Principles and Practice of Remote Sensing
- · Visual Analytics
- · Environmental Modelling
- · Advanced Spatial Databases
- · Environmental Modelling
- · Research Practice and Project Planning

Dissertation: Developing an interactive web map for historical analysis in Islay, Scotland-including adding base maps as Web Map Services.

BSc. Surveying and Geoinformatics University of Lagos | 2011 – 2016

1st Class Honours (4.60 out of 5)

Skills developed include: Effective teamwork, data analyses, writing clear and concise reports and clear presentation of data in appropriate forms.

Additionally, advanced skills in land survey, spatial analysis, GPS field data collection, map projections and hydrography.

Dissertation: Smart cities concept on smart commuting - Developed an Android app using the Android SDK to aid smart commuting in Lagos, Nigeria.

AWARDS

- Head of School Scholarship Geosciences, 2017(University of Edinburgh)
- Scholarship for Academic Excellence 2017(Fugro Nigeria Limited)
- •Endowment Scholarship for Academic Excellence 2016 (University of Lagos)

VOLUNTEERING

Created a small tutor group to mentor and coach young students in preparation for their West African Examination Council (WAEC) exams in Lagos, Nigeria.

LANGUAGES

- English
- .French
- Arabic
- ·Yoruba

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- ·Fitness enthusiast
- Hiking
- Travelling
- Footballing

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Intern Interspatial Technologies, Lagos | DEC 2016 – SEP 2017

- Preparing flood risk maps with LiDAR data using various GIS and modelling systems such as ArcPy, ESRI's model builder, HEC-HMS and HEC-RAS
- Providing regular progress report and flooding information to supervisors and clients and ensuring end documents satisfy their requirements.
- Managing various spatial data and data and information systems in line with internal policies, procedures, and best practice and ensuring databases are up to date.

Undergraduate Intern Interspatial Technologies, Lagos | JUL 2015 - DEC 2015

- Collection and mapping of field data with Trimble Juno using ArcPad
- Undertaking perimeter survey of land parcels using DGPS in line with client requirements
- Map digitization and creation of survey plans using ArcGIS and AutoCAD respectively.
- Ensuring proper conversion of CAD data to GIS formats to be overlain on orthophotos

CONTINUOUS PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- GIS Research UK (GISRUK) 2018
- AGI Conference 2018
- GeoData Aware 2017
- · ArcGIS Pro Online courses

RFFFRFNCFS

Available Upon Request